《絕命律師》前情提要
Previously on "Better Call Saul"
真不敢相信戴維斯梅因會支持你
I can't believe Davis and Main went for it.
你真以為我會同意嗎
Did you actually think that was gonna fly?
-這可不是你  -明早八點到我辦公室來
- You can't--  - Tomorrow morning, eight o'clock, my office,
合伙人也在  把你拍的那玩意兒也帶來
with the partners, and we wanna see this thing.
這其中可能存在教唆之嫌
There may have been some solicitation.
為了給你弄到這份工作  我拿我的飯碗作擔保
I put myself on the line to get you this job.
所以呢...這算是你幫了我嗎
So what, you threw me a bone?
是我的承諾  是我的判斷
It's my word. It's my judgement.
你想多賺點  就要做相應的工作
You want next level pay, you gotta do next level work.
說吧  你把我叫來這里什么事
You wanna tell me what we're doing here?
有個人
There's a guy.
我想要他消失
I need him to go away.
絕命律師
第二季 第四集
翻譯  喃喃  自然卷  喵球球
我丈夫和我節衣縮食過了很多年
My husband and I scrimped and saved for so many years.
為了不成為家庭的負擔
We did our best to build a nest egg
翻譯  肉松  joy_bwl
我們盡力攢下了一筆養老金
so that we wouldn't be a burden to our family.
校對  喃喃 肉松
羅納德去世后  我搬進了一家生活協助中心
After Ronald passed, I moved to an assisted-living facility --
很不錯的地方
a nice place.
時間軸  喃喃  姜姜  念念
后期  四月追番的小新     總監  喃喃
他們說會照顧好一切
They told me they'd take care of everything,
但有一天  他們說我一分錢都沒了
but then, one day, they said all my money was gone.
怎么會這樣
How could that be?
錢都去哪兒了
Where did it all go?
如果你或愛人
If you or a loved one
是磯鷂渡生活協助中心
is a resident of a Sandpiper crossing facility
或是其他有關退休社區的居民
or other associated retirement community...
天啊  你自己配的音嗎
Jesus. ‭You used your own voice?
你也許有資格
...You may be eligible to
-獲得補償  -為了省錢
- receive compensation. - Strictly to save money.
-總的算下來  才花了  -行了
- All in, the whole thing cost -- - Just --
如需免費咨詢
For a free consultation,
請致電戴維斯梅因律所
call the law offices of Davis & Main
電話505-242-7700
at 505-242-7700.
That's 505-242-7700.
制作成本總共才647美元
The production costs -- $647, all in.
播出一次的廣告費才七百  便宜到家了
The one single airing was a $700 ad buy, so dirt-cheap.
你覺得這是因為錢嗎
You think this is about money?
我們找你來是因為錢嗎
You think that's what this is about?
我只是盡量提供全面的信息
I'm just trying to offer complete information here.
這次播出  只是一個實驗
Now, this one airing -- it was an experiment,
而且不管怎么說  都是一次成功的實驗
and as such, by any measure, a success.
你一直說"實驗實驗"
You keep using the word "Experiment"
好像你是該死的萊特兄弟似的
like you're ‭the goddamned Wright brothers.
你到底準備什么時候告訴我們這個"實驗"
When exactly were you gonna tell us about this experiment?
今天
Today.
就今早
This morning.
我承認我有點操之過急了
I-I admit, I got a little ahead of myself,
有點過于激動了
a little...exuberant.
我為此道歉
And for that, I apologize.
但我認為最重要的是
But the headline here is -- I think --
廣告播出后我們已經接到將近兩百通來電了
we've gotten nearly 200 phone calls since this one airing.
克利福德  昨晚我倆聊過后
Cliff, since you and I spoke last night,
又多了七十二通
72 more.
聽到了嗎  外面響起的就是勝利的號角
You hear that? Right there -- that's the sound of victory.
吉米  別自圓其說了
Jimmy, stop selling.
別裝作對真正的問題視而不見
And don't act like ‭you don't see the problem here.
我沒覺得有問題啊
I don't.
你不跟我們打招呼
You cut us out.
繞過我們自行其是
You did an end run around us.
"過于激動"才不是什么借口
Exuberance is no excuse.
克利福德
Cliff.
客戶聯系由我負責
Client outreach is my department.
你第一天就跟我說清楚了
Now, you told me that from day one.
吉米  那如果我讓你負責發工資
Jimmy, if I put you in charge of payroll, would that mean
那你給每個人發一百萬獎金我都得同意咯
I'd be okay with you giving everyone a million-dollar bonus?
我倆討論過廣告的可行性啊
You and I did discuss the possibility of a commercial.
理論上的可行性而已
The possibility in the abstract,
而且還是我出門之前的短短三十秒內談的
for a grand total of 30 seconds when I was halfway out the door.
我還以為我聽出了你的熱情
I guess -- I thought I heard enthusiasm,
所以我就稍微自作主張了點
so I-I took some initiative.
"稍微"
"Some."
戴維斯梅因是個團隊
We are a team at Davis & Main.
講究的是團隊合作
This is a team approach.
你來之前還是個獨立從業者
You coming to us ‭as a solo practitioner --
我知道你還需要一段時間的學習
I knew there was gonna be a learning curve.
但如果你就是學不會融入這個團隊
But if you simply can't fit in as part of the team --
我可以融入  我融入了啊
I can fit in. I-I fit in.
我是來幫你們和HHM打贏磯鷂渡的官司的
I am here to help you and HHM win Sandpiper.
所以我才會這么做
That's all this was about.
我們可沒指望著磯鷂渡過活
Sandpiper's not what keeps the lights on around here.
我們有的客戶不想跟這種...東西
We have clients who wouldn't want to be associated
聯系在一起
with this kind of... this.
我們的形象和名譽
Our image, our reputation
是我們小心經營多年才打造起來的
is something we've been carefully building for years.
比任何案子都重要
It's worth far more than any one case.
這樣的行為會損害名譽
Something like this could damage it.
這么說吧
Suffice it to say,
現在我們幾位都對你沒什么好感
there's not a lot of love for you in the room at the moment.
投票結果二比一  要因為你的不當行為解雇你
The vote is currently two to one to fire you for cause.
不過
However...
我相信要給人第二次機會
I believe in second chances.
但是再犯一次就三振出局
But know this is both strike one and strike two.
三振出局法
有兩次犯罪前科的罪犯第三次犯罪時從重量刑
今后你將受到更嚴格的監督
Going forward, you can expect a great deal more scrutiny.
快接  快接
Come on. Come on.
你好
Hello.
這是金·韋克斯勒的語音信箱
You've reached the voicemail of Kim Wexler.
請留言
Please leave me a message,
我會盡快回復你
And I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
金
Hey, kim.
盡快打給我  好嗎
I need you to call me as soon as you can, all right?
時間很關鍵
It's a time-sensitive thing, so, uh,
我是說  我可能...
I mean, I may have, uh, just --
麻煩你在跟霍華德談之前打給我好嗎
Well, please call me before you talk to Howard, okay?
再見
Bye.
未接來電
一條語音消息
很簡單的問題  金
It's a simple question, Kim --
你知不知道這條廣告
Did you or did you not know about this commercial?
我知道
I -- yes.
他給我看了
He showed it to me.
他給你看了嗎
He showed it to you?
是的  幾天前
Yes. A few days ago.
這事兒你沒跟任何人說嗎
And you didn't say anything to anyone?
沒有
No. I didn't.
你不覺得該跟我說一聲嗎
You didn't think I deserved a heads-up?
我沒想到
I didn't realize --
當時我覺得沒必要
At the time, ‭I didn't think it was necessary.
那你想錯了
Well, you were wrong about that.
我們被合伙律師問了個措手不及
We were caught flat-footed in front of our co-counsel,
不用我跟你解釋  這對HHM的影響很不好
which I don't need to tell you, does not reflect well on HHM.
對你也不好
Or on you.
就這樣吧
That'll be all.
你可以走了
You can go.
你準備怎么辦
What are you going to do?
你覺得呢
So, what do you think?
我覺得從這里可以很清楚地觀察對面
I figure from here, you've got a good bead on the place,
但里面的人  他們發現不了你
but someone inside -- they can't pick you out.
屠庫和我  就在那里
Tuco and me -- that's our spot.
他總是面朝外坐著
He always sits facing out,
把這搞得像黑幫一樣
makes it look like it's a gangster thing,
但他是為了盯著自己的車
but I know it's just so he can keep an eye on his ride.
每個周二  我們都來這里收賬
Every Tuesday, ‭we're here squaring accounts.
毒販子過來  付掉欠款
Dealer comes in, pays what he owes.
屠庫  他喜歡跟他們面對面
Tuco -- he likes to get face-to-face.
他說他想要知道的一切都寫在臉上
Says everything he needs to know is written right here.
看著他們的眼睛
Looks 'em in the eyes.
死盯著  好像要把他們看穿
Just stares, like he's looking inside of 'em.
我見過他一盯就盯上五分鐘十分鐘
I've seen him go like that 5, 10 minutes.
為什么要那么做
And what does that accomplish?
他把這叫做測謊儀
Calls it his lie detector.
所以這事得持續一整天
That's why these things go all day.
就你倆嗎  沒幫手了嗎
Just the two of you? No extra muscle?
不需要  我們自己能搞定
Don't need it. ‭We can handle our business.
不過得花好幾個鐘頭
Anyway, it takes hours.
收錢  數錢  測謊
Collect the cash, count it, lie detector.
一次一個  人進來  交易  然后下一個
One at a time -- guy comes in, transacts, then the next.
完事之后  屠庫上他的車  我上我的
Then, when we're done, Tuco gets in his car, I get in mine.
然后各走各的
Boom. We go our separate ways.
這時候就該你上了
That is where you come in.
當你看到他在收拾了  就開過去
You see him packing up -- wsssh -- drive over.
停在屠庫旁邊的車位
Pull up in the spot next to Tuco's.
砰  爆頭
Pop. Head shot.
開車走人  很簡單
Roll out. Easy.
40號公路的上匝道就在那邊八個街區外
I-40 onramp is eight blocks up.
別人還沒反應過來  你就已經沒了蹤影
You're in the wind ‭before anyone has time to blink.
更好的是  這些毒販子
And here's the beauty -- all these, um, dealers?
都知道我們在這  所以故事可以這么編
They know we're here, so the story is,
他們其中一個想要殺死屠庫
one of them got ideas, decided to kill Tuco,
從這生意中撈一筆
get a cut of the business.
在販毒集團看來  可能是任何一個人
Could've been any of them, as far as the cartel's concerned.
這些星期二
These Tuesdays of yours --
結束的時候是白天還是晚上
Day or night when you wrap it up?
-白天  -所以就是光天化日
- Day. - ‭So, full daylight.
過往車輛也很多
Plenty of traffic.
我怎樣才能不被看見呢
How exactly do I not get seen?
我的車總會被看見吧
My car, at least.
會出錯的  終將出錯
墨菲定律告訴我  有人會記下車牌的
Murphy's Law tells me somebody's gonna pull a plate.
好吧  那就去車場買輛舊車
Fine. ‭Go to the yard. Buy a beater.
你就待在車里
You're gonna stay in the car.
沒人會看見你
‭Ain't no one gonna see you.
就算看到你了  那又怎樣
And if they do see you, so what?
這就是你為什么是完美人選
That's why you're perfect.
你很不起眼  沒什么聯系
You're no one. You got no connections.
你就是個幽靈
You're a ghost.
所以我停在他旁邊
So, I pull in next to him --
那得假定有停車的地方
That assumes there's a parking spot.
毒販子都停在他車旁邊
Our guys park next to him.
來去都是同一個車位
They come and go from the same spot.
最后一個人走了  你就可以上了
Last one takes off, you're open.
要是有人停在我后面  我就被堵了
Someone comes in behind me, I'm blocked.
誰會停在你后面啊
Who's gonna pull in behind you?
來吃玉米卷餅的人
Well, I'm guessing someone who likes tacos.
那該怎么辦
What then?
我該怎么離開
What's my exit?
不知道
I don't know.
下車跑路
Get out and run.
我膝蓋不好
Bad knees.
我付錢就是讓你搞定這些細節的
Look, the details -- that's what I'm paying you for.
你要是有更好的計劃  請告訴我
You've got a better plan, go on, tell me.
我洗耳恭聽
I'm all ears.
你確定要這么干嗎
You sure about this?
殺死你的同伙
Killing your partner --
干了就沒有回頭路了
that's a bell you don't un-ring.
看到了嗎
See this?
你知道這是怎么弄的嗎
You know how I got this?
九六  九七年的時候  屠庫和我
Back in '96, '97, Tuco and I
和一群河濱縣的飛車黨合作
were working with these bikers out of Riverside County.
他們賣低純度冰毒
They were running ‭this peanut-butter crank --
質量次得很
Real shit, y'know?
但是便宜  我們拿到手很快就賣完了
But cheap, and we could sell it as fast as we got it.
后來屠庫也用上了
Anyway, ‭Tuco develops a taste for it.
這毒品把人變得很壞
And crank does not bring out the best in people.
讓屠庫發瘋
Made Tuco erratic.
我們的聯絡人是一個叫道格·保爾森的人
Our connect ‭was a guy called Dawg Paulson.
有一天  屠庫和道格見面
One day, ‭Tuco's settling up with Dawg.
決定對他測測謊
He decides ‭to put on his lie detector.
道格說"你要干嘛"
Dawg's like, ‭"What the hell?" You know.
屠庫就一直死盯著他
Tuco just keeps staring at him.
然后他就不說話了
Then he goes real quiet.
"你覺得我是傻逼嗎  道格"
"You think I'm an idiot, Dawg?"
他認為道格在給他的競爭對手供貨
He thinks Dawg is supplying his competitor,
想要把屠庫取代
trying to cut Tuco out.
道格矢口否認
Dawg -- he denies it.
"不可能  不是我"
"No way! Not me!"
屠庫都沒有提高嗓門  但突然間
Tuco doesn't even ‭raise his voice, but suddenly,
他掏出削短霰彈槍
he's got a sawed-off and...
一槍崩了道格的臉
right in Dawg's face.
我就站在他身后
I was behind him.
那是我至今為止見過最惡心的畫面
Sickest thing I ever saw, to this day.
而這
And this?
是道格的頭骨碎片
A piece of Dawg's skull --
一小塊鉆到皮膚下面去了
Under the skin, a little piece of him.
我試過挖出來  但它就是不肯出來
I tried digging it out, but it's in there pretty good.
這事可不能去找醫生
Anyway, not the kinda thing you go to the doctor's for.
其實我想說  屠庫很喜歡道格
The thing about it was, Tuco really liked dawg.
后來他也有點后悔
Kind of felt bad afterwards.
但當他吸了毒  就瘋了
But when he's using, loco, crazy.
根本無法形容
There's no other way to put it.
現在他又開始吸毒了
And he's using again.
純度更高的  勁兒更大
Crystal -- much bigger kick.
所以跟你說的一樣
So... It's like you said.
如果屠庫發現了我在外面的私活兒
If Tuco finds out about my, y'know, independent ventures,
我就會落得跟道格一樣的下場
it's gonna be Dawg all over again.
有我沒他
It's him or me.
那里
There.
用裝了瞄準器的槍就可以擊中
A man with a scoped rifle could get a clean shot.
就一發子彈
Fire a single round,
在大家反應過來之前消失
disappear before anybody knew what had happened.
沒有目擊者  還可以順利逃脫
No witnesses. Clean egress.
很遠啊
Pretty far.
你打得中嗎
You can make that shot?
打得中
Yeah.
你同意干了嗎
You saying you'll do it?
五萬
50 grand?
那就五萬
50 grand.
我去看看
I'll look into it.
你哥哥不在這  麥吉爾先生
Your brother isn't here, Mr. Mcgill.
我知道
I know.
他讓我來拿他的吸墨紙
Uh, he sent me to get his ink blotter.
-就一會  -小心點
- I'll just be a second. - ‭Watch yourself.
地很滑
The floor's slick.
多謝  杰蘇阿爾多
Oh, thank you, Gesualdo.
抱歉踩臟了
Sorry about the floor!
不是吧
Oh, no.
你在找韋克斯勒小姐嗎
Are you looking for Ms. Wexler?
沒趕上  是吧
I guess I'm too late, huh?
不  她還沒走
No, she's still here.
在哪
Where?
金
Kim.
我非常  非常抱歉
I am so, so sorry.
我昨晚就應該告訴你的
I should have told you last night.
是嗎
You think?
我真以為我能解決的
I honestly thought I could fix it.
我以為他們一看到數字就懂了
I thought they'd understand once they saw the numbers.
我知道廣告會有用  也確實如此
I knew it would work, and it did.
真的有效
It worked.
霍華德不能因為我做的事
Howard can't just stick you in doc review
就把你弄來復審文件
because of something I did.
而且我倆在兩家不同的律所
Plus, at an ‭entirely different law firm.
完全沒有道理啊
What the hell kind of sense does that make?!
我告訴過你后果
I told you this would happen.
他不能因為這事怪你
He can't blame you for this.
我警告過你他會的
I warned you he would.
我要去找霍華德
I'm talking to Howard.
干什么  再罵他是卑鄙無恥的豬嗎
What? And call him a pig fucker again?
是啊  會有用的
Yeah, that'll help.
我搞砸了
I screwed up, you know?
我知道
I know that.
但這...  這完全是扯淡
But this -- this is total B.S.!
我今晚就去找他談
I'm -- ‭I'm talking to him tonight!
吉米別去  你只會弄得更糟
Jimmy, no. ‭You'd only make things worse.
-我會向他解釋  -不用
- I'll explain it to him. - ‭No!
我不是請求你  而是告訴你
I'm not asking you -- I'm telling you.
如果你去找霍華德  你和我就沒戲了
If you go to Howard, you and I -- we're done.
那我們現在還有戲嗎
So, we're not done now?
我需要這份工作
I need this job.
每周開票限額要四十個小時才能審完
And there's a weekly billing quota that I'm about 40 hours behind on,
所以可以請你離開嗎
so could you please just go?
對不起
I'm sorry.
查克
Chuck!
快開門
Come on!
我不會走的
I'm not going away!
好  你自找的
All right, you asked for it!
我進來了
I'm comin' in!
查克
Chuck?
能聽見我說話嗎
Can you hear me?
能說話嗎
Can you talk to me?
要我送你去醫院嗎
Do you want me ‭to get you to the hospital?
不  不去醫院
No. No hospitals.
我會好的
I'll -- I'll be all right.
請給我點水
Get some water, please.
給你額外的保護
Extra protection here.
給  這樣
Here. You know what?
坐起來
Sit up.
你能坐起來嗎
Can you sit?
好的
All right.
好了
Okay. All right.
拿著
Here.
這是阿瑪利特AR-50狙擊步槍
That's the Armalite AR-50 --
制造技術先進  射程精確到兩千四百米
State of the art, ‭accurate to 2,400 meters.
裝備了里奧波特Mark4瞄準鏡
I got the Leupold mark 4 on it now,
但我可以幫你升級到施密特本德的
but I can always upgrade you to a Schmidt & Bender.
手動單發
Single shot, bolt.
簡單  有效  值得信賴
Simple, effective, reliable.
用的是0.50直徑的子彈
It fires the .50-caliber BMG --
對輕型掩體內的軟目標很有效
Very effective against soft targets in light cover --
可以射穿汽車  小樹等等
behind cars, ‭small-diameter trees, and such.
與往常一樣  我已經特意
As always, I've gone to the trouble
磨掉了序列號
of grinding down the serial number.
除非你徹底磨個洞
Well, unless you ‭ground a hole clean through,
否則用酸都可以復原
acid will recover it.
說得沒錯
Well, that would be true,
但我又用隨機點刻壓力機做了處理
but I follow up with a pass through ‭a random-stipple machine press.
把它藏在金屬密度中
Hides the patterns in the metal density.
應該可以逃過X射線衍射
Should throw off your X-ray diffraction
還有其他高科技手段的檢測
and some other higher-end methods.
當然萬事無完美  但這槍接近完美了
Nothing's perfect, of course, but this is close.
就像疝氣上多了個瞄準鏡
Looks like a hernia with a scope on it.
三十四磅
34 pounds,
不包括你的槍架  那也會增加重量
not including your bipod, which adds some heft.
太重了
Too much gun.
我同意  對于大多數場合確實重
For most applications, I would tend to agree.
SR-25比賽步槍  尤金·斯通勒設計  半自動
SR-25 match rifle -- Eugene Stoner design, semi-auto.
大概十一磅
That's about 11 pounds there.
沒有AR-50的射程和穿透力
Not quite the range or the punch of the AR-50,
但射程就算有一千米
but you're still talking about a .5 M.O.A.
射擊精度也高達0.5MOA
at well past 1,000 meters.
我聽說容易卡殼
I've heard they're prone to jam.
確實在實戰中會發生
Well, it's been known to happen in the field,
但沒有一把半自動步槍可以自吹不卡殼的
but there's not a semi-auto built can boast it never jams.
如果你有所顧慮  你應該選擇手動式的
If that's a concern, you ought to stick to bolts.
好的手動步槍如果都能卡殼
Good bolt-action rifle -- if you jammed it,
那我打賭你肯定是故意的
I'd wager ‭you were setting out to do so.
我們來看看這把M40
Which brings us to the M40 --
十分可靠  經過戰斗檢驗
Tried and true, battle-tested.
自從1966年
Essentially, the same rifle
海軍陸戰隊狙擊手就用這種槍了
used by marine snipers since 1966.
輕便精準  適合在八百到一千二百米之內
It's light, accurate, good for soft targets
射擊軟目標
in the 800- to 1,2000-meter range.
看起來你了解這把槍
You seem to know this one.
那當然
Oh, yeah.
可以這么說
You could say that.
那是A1型
That's the A1 model.
在原版基礎上變化不大
There's not much change from the original.
最大的不同在于槍托
Biggest difference is the stock --
不是木制的  改成玻璃纖維了
it's fiberglass instead of wood.
1970年左右改的
It changed it over in 1970 or so.
好的  木頭太容易變形
Good. Wood warped like hell.
要是受了潮  又被曝曬  就完了
You get it wet, ‭you put it in the sun -- gone.
這槍被帶到叢林里使用之前
Somebody probably ‭should've figured that out
那些人真該想到這點
before they sent it into a damn jungle.
是啊  也許吧
Yeah. Probably.
如果這些都不喜歡
If these aren't to your liking,
我可以再弄幾支來
I could get my hands on a few more.
不用了
No.
我改主意了
I've changed my mind.
謝謝
Thank you.
這次我不需要槍
I don't need anything at this time.
麻煩你了
For your trouble.
不客氣
Oh, it's no trouble.
我做的都是回頭生意
I make my living on repeat business.
等你有需要  就來找我
When you need what I'm offering, you know how to find me.
你還在這啊
You're still here.
是的  我還在
Yeah, I'm still here.
你睡覺了嗎
Did you get any sleep?
睡了一會
Some.
足夠了
Enough.
你感覺怎么樣
‭How you feeling?
我想喝點茶
I could use some tea.
謝謝
Thanks.
你昨晚嚇到我了
‭You scared me last night.
是啊  有時候會這樣
Yeah. Happens sometimes.
有時候是我太過火了  僅此而已
Sometimes, I overdo it -- that's all.
都會好的
It passes.
去辦公室把你累得筋疲力竭吧
Going into the office really takes it out of you, doesn't it?
如果待的太久  是很累
If I stay too long, yeah.
大概是走不開吧
Guess it's hard not to stay.
畢竟有那么多重要的事要你來做
There's so many important things for you to do there --
比如懲罰金·韋克斯勒
like, you know, stick it to Kim Wexler.
我對金·韋克斯勒做什么了
What did I do to Kim Wexler?
她又回"玉米地"了  不是嗎
She's back in the cornfield, isn't she?
我什么都沒對金做
I didn't do anything to Kim.
我當時確實在場
I mean, I was present, yes.
但是人事管理的決策都是霍華德做的
But management of personnel -- those decisions are all Howard's.
可笑
That is rich.
那你告訴我
But tell me,
霍華德做"管理決策"的時候
when Howard was makin' his "management decisions,"
把霍華德比作戴在手上的布偶
是坐在你膝蓋上  你把手伸進他屁眼了嗎
was he sitting on your knee with your arm up his ass?
你喝水的時候他是不是都說不出話
Hey, can he talk while you drink a glass of water?
你這樣說沒有道理
That's uncalled-for.
如果霍華德是我的布偶
And if howard were my puppet,
他才不會推薦你去戴維斯梅因律所
he certainly wouldn't have recommended you to Davis & Main.
實際上  我確定是金·韋克斯勒
Actually, I'm sure it was Kim Wexler
說服他這樣做的  所以他才生氣
who talked him into doing that. Hence his anger.
別懲罰金
Don't punish Kim.
如果你生我的氣  那就沖我來
If you're mad at me, take it out on me.
你覺得整個世界都圍著你轉  吉米
I know you like to think the world revolves around you, Jimmy,
但這和你無關
but this has nothing to do with you.
金對哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所負責
Kim had a responsibility to Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill.
她本該為自己律所的利益著想
She should have been looking out for her firm's interests.
沒告訴我們你要干什么是她的錯
Not letting us know what you were up to was her mistake.
拜托
Oh, come on.
你不能為這事生她的氣
You can't be pissed off at her about this.
我沒生氣
I'm not.
霍華德才生氣
Howard is.
他憑什么不生氣呢
And why shouldn't he be?
因為她不知道
Because she didn't know.
她不知道我會播出廣告
She didn't know I was gonna air the commercial.
也不知道我還沒得到許可
She didn't know ‭i hadn't gotten it approved.
她不知道
She just -- she didn't know.
-我懂了  -所以她不知道
- I see. - So, she didn't know
她應該事先通知霍華德什么
there was anything that she was supposed to tell Howard.
她以為克利福德已經知情了
As far as she was concerned, Cliff Main was already looped in.
你跟她說他知道了
You told her he was?
我是這么暗示的
I implied it.
所以錯在我  不在她
So it's on me, not her.
她沒跟我們說這些啊
She didn't say anything to us about that.
她不會說的
Well, she wouldn't.
她不想讓我看起來很蠢
Sh-she wouldn't want to make me look bad.
你不能否認  這說明她缺乏判斷
You have to admit this shows a lack of judgment on her part.
她了解你
She knows you.
她應該采取正確的做法的
She should have known better.
你真是個混蛋
You are such an asshole.
我怎么了
Why?
我不就是指出  她信任你是個錯誤嗎
For pointing out that her one mistake was believing in you?
天啊  能不能正確看待這件事
For Christ's sake, can we get some perspective here?
這只是個小廣告
It was a simple, little commercial.
只播出了一次  僅此而已
It aired once -- that's all.
要不要我提醒你  它非常有效
And can I remind you -- it worked.
效果驚人得好
It worked like a dream.
看到你的問題了吧  吉米
See, that's your problem, Jimmy --
你認為只要結果好  手段都不重要
thinking the ends justify the means.
壞事了以后你又總是覺得震驚
And you're forever shocked when it all blows up in your face.
我犯了什么不得了的大錯
What did I do that was so wrong?
你壞了規矩
you broke the rules.
你讓金變成了你的從犯
‭You turned Kim into your accessory.
你讓霍華德難堪  可憐的人啊
You embarrassed Howard, who -- god help him --
他居然莫名其妙地在克利福德面前為你擔保
inexplicably vouched for you with Cliff Main!
克利福德和他的合伙人被你弄得像蠢貨
You made Cliff and his partners look like schmucks!
還要我繼續說嗎
Shall I go on?!
我簡直搞不懂他為什么沒炒了你
How he hasn't fired you for this positively mystifies me.
還"正確看待"
"Perspective."
你要正確地看待嗎
You want perspective?
那我給你說
I'll give you mine --
你是我弟弟  我很愛你
you're my brother and I love you,
但是你就像個酒鬼
but you're like an alcoholic
拒絕承認自己有毛病
who refuses to admit he's got a problem.
現在有人給了你校車的鑰匙
Now someone's given you the keys to the school bus,
我才不會讓你把它開下懸崖
and I'm not gonna let you drive it off a cliff!
我們能直接說要點嗎
Now, can we just get down to brass tacks here?
我要做什么才能讓金回到她的崗位
What can I do to put Kim back where she belongs, huh?
你希望我退出戴維斯梅因律所嗎
What -- you want me to quit Davis & Main?
那好
That's fine.
我當初就沒想要那份工作
I-I never wanted that job in the first place.
跟你說不清楚
I can't get through to you.
生活不是《做交易》的那種游戲
Life is not one big game of "Let's Make a Deal"!
一檔游戲節目  蒙蒂·霍爾曾擔任主持人
就是  我是蒙蒂·霍爾
Yes, it is! ‭I'm Monty Hall!
二號門后面是什么
What's behind door number two?
有什么代價
What'll it take, huh?!
你想讓我退出律師行業嗎
You want me to quit being a lawyer?
像猩猩拿著一把機關槍
Ju-- a chimp with a machine gun --
說的是我  對吧
That's me, right, huh?!
你覺得呢
So, what do you say?
你幫金  我不當律師了
You help Kim -- I quit the law.
-成交嗎  -我沒那么說
- Is that a deal? - ‭I didn't say that.
你嘴上沒說  但心里卻這么想  是吧
No, you didn't say it, but that's what you want, right?!
所以你當初才強迫她
That's why you put the screws to Kim in the first place --
為了逼我
to squeeze me!
我沒那么說  我也不會那么說
I didn't say that, ‭and I would never say that!
為什么
Why not?!
因為如果我阻礙我一個雇員的職業道路
Because if I were impeding the career of one of my employees
是為了逼你做你不愿意做的事
for the purpose of compelling you to do something against your will,
那就是敲詐
that would be extortion.
沒錯
Yeah. ‭
就是  那么
It would. So?
你要敲詐我嗎  查克
You gonna extort me, Chuck?
那你肯定能輕而易舉脫罪
It's a lead-pipe cinch you'd get away with it.
我不會告訴任何人
I'm not gonna tell anyone.
很簡單  只要恢復金的職位
It's real easy -- you just set things right for Kim.
讓她回原來的辦公室  不再復審文件
You get her back in her office, out of doc review --
一切回歸原樣  我永遠不當律師了
Everything back to normal, and I quit the law for good.
不再有吉米·麥吉爾先生  沒了
No more Jimmy McGill, esquire -- poof!
就像沒存在過
Like he never even existed.
但我得聽你親口說出來  行嗎
But I need to hear the words come out of your mouth, okay?
你言而有信
‭You're a man of your word.
你是誠實的人  對吧
You're an upstanding man, right?
-天啊  吉米  -快說  查克
- For god's sake, Jimmy. ‭- Come on, chuck!
敲詐我
Extort me!
說"別干"  我就不干了
Say "quit," and I will quit,
但我得聽你親口說
but I need to hear it from your mouth!
你想讓我犯下重罪嗎
You want me to commit a felony...
這才是你的目的  對吧
Because that's what you'd do, right?
因為你想要相信  我其實是個偽君子
Because you want to believe that deep down, I'm some hypocrite!
很快就知道了
Let's find out.
來吧  查克
Come on down, Chuck!
跟我一起在地上打滾吧
Roll around in the dirt with me!
你會實現所有的夢想
All your dreams will come true!
來  快  快說
Go on! Do it! Go on!
我不是壞人
I am not the bad guy here.
你不想當律師
You don't want to be a lawyer --
那是你和新墨西哥州律師界的事
that's between you ‭and the New Mexico State bar.
你想離開戴維斯梅因律所  隨便你
You want to quit Davis & Main? Be my guest!
你想自毀前途顯然不需要我的幫助
You clearly don't need any help from me to tank your career.
你自己犯的事足矣
You're doing just fine on your own.
說到自毀前途  去圣達菲要一小時車程
Speaking of which, it's an hour's drive to Santa Fe.
就算你現在走
Even if you leave right now,
上班還得遲到至少二十分鐘
you're still gonna be at least 20 minutes late for work --
克利福德·梅因對你的印象會雪上加霜
another feather in your cap with Clifford Main.
怎么樣
So?
我不干了
I'm not gonna do it.
怎么  你想談判嗎
What -- ‭are you negotiating now?
錢再多這也還是個餿主意  對你來說
No amount of money makes this a good idea -- for you.
聽著  伙計  我說了我沒...
Look, man, ‭I told you that I'm not --
這樣不好  因為解決不了你的實際問題
No, it's a bad move because it doesn't solve your real problem.
實際問題是什么
My real problem? What's that?
不是屠庫
It's not Tuco.
而是保密
It's keeping a secret.
屠庫的死會把塞拉曼加的人像蒼蠅一樣引來
A dead Tuco ‭draws Salamancas like flies.
販毒集團會打探此事
The cartel noses into the business,
尋找殺害同伙的人
looks for who hit one of theirs.
你那時還能保密嗎
You gonna be able to keep your secrets then?
總要付出代價
Something's got to give.
有沒有你  都無所謂
With you, without you -- I don't care.
總會發生的
But something's gonna happen.
你自己也說了
You said it yourself.
你不需要他死  你需要他離開
You don't need him dead -- you need him to go away.
你是說告密嗎
You mean snitch?
我打了屠庫的小報告
Man, I drop a dime on Tuco,
你覺得集團會懷疑誰
who do you think the cartel looks at?
我
Me.
如果報警  我也會被抓
And if I call the cops, I get picked up, too.
我就成了已知關聯人
I'm what you call a known associate.
他們把我跟屠庫關在一起
So I'm locked up with Tuco,
而他正在找讓他被關起來的人
who's looking for the guy that put him there.
告訴我那樣怎么能幫我
Tell me how that helps me.
你不用跟警察說
You won't have to talk to the cops.
任何時候都不用
You won't have to do any time.
不會死人  但屠庫的問題
There's no killing, but your Tuco problem?
會解決的
It goes away.
都在這兒了
It's all there.
讓他點點
Let the man count.
沒問題
We're good.
那...下次再見
So, uh... till next time, huh?
屠庫
Tuco.
行
Okay.
走
Go.
行
Okay.
下周再見  屠庫
I'll, uh... ‭I'll see you next week, Tuco.
納喬
Nacho.
再見  多明戈
Yeah, see you, Domingo.
他給錢還挺多
He's got good numbers.
挺拼命的
He's hustlin'.
你覺得呢
What do you think?
可靠嗎
Solid?
電話
沒錯  我想報告一起沖突
Uh, uh, y-yes, I would like to report a fight going on
發生在伊斯萊塔大道五千街區的
at the El Michoacano restaurant in the 5000 block of
米卻肯飯店
the Isleta Boulevard.
有個男人用槍威脅另一個男人
There's a man threatening another man with a gun.
看著像黑幫鬧事
It looks to be some sort of gang thing.
抱歉
Oh, uh, uh, uh, sorry.
我  我只是個過路的
I-I -- I'm a passerby.
我可不想卷進去
I-I don't want to get involved.
他媽的
The fuck.
你看到了嗎
Did you see that?
看到什么
See what?
那個老頭撞了我的車
That old man just hit my car.
你好
Hello. Oh. Hmm.
我看看
Well, let me see.
我要四號餐和雞塊  麻煩你了
Give me the number four, the pollo, por favor.
-打包帶走  -好的  先生
- That's to go. - ‭Yes, sir.
你
Hey, you.
老頭
Hey, gramps.
你撞到我的車了
You just hit my car.
你在跟我說話嗎
Uh, you're talking to me?
馬古先生來了
Check out Mr. Magoo here.
卡通人物
形象為與麥克神似的光頭老者
是的  先生
Uh, y-yes, sir.
看到停在你那破車旁邊的那輛車了嗎
You see that car that you parked your piece of shit next to?
是我的
That's mine.
你剛剛撞到它了
You just ran into it.
不  我想我沒有
No, I don't think I did.
那你是說我撒謊了
You calling me a liar?
我沒這么說
Uh, no.
我也看到了
Hey. I saw it, too.
你打算否認嗎
You gonna stand here and deny it?
小伙子們  我不知道該怎么跟你們說
Um, guys, um, I-I don't know what to tell you.
我不知道我撞了誰的車
I'm not aware ‭of hitting anyone's car,
但如果我真撞到了  那我道歉
but if I did... I apologize.
-所以  -六塊三毛三
- So... - ‭$6.33.
不用找了
You keep the change.
謝謝
Thank you.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你給我站住
Don't you walk away from me.
老頭  你最好聽他的話
Hey, pops. You better listen to the man.
得了吧伙計們
Come on, guys.
咱們友好一點  行嗎
Let's just keep things friendly, all right?
我不是你朋友
I ain't your friend.
你看
Look!
看到沒有  你干的好事
You see that? You -- you did that.
拜托  那點東西一擦就掉了
Oh, come on. That'll buff right out.
你給我處理好
You're gonna make this all right.
否則不許走
You're not leaving until you do.
行  你有筆嗎
Fine. You got a pen?
筆
A pen.
筆  留下彼此的信息  保險
A pen -- we'll exchange information, insurance.
我的保險挺全的
I have very good coverage.
保險公司會處理的
They'll take care of this.
別跟我說什么保險
I'm not messing around with insurance, ése.
我要現金
Cash.
聽著  我愿意承擔責任
Listen, I'm willing to accept responsibility,
但你要是不想通過保險公司
but if you're not going through insurance,
我身上只有二三十塊錢  我只有這些
then I have maybe 20, 30 bucks on me -- that's all.
現在是你在說謊了
Kay, now you're lying to me.
我看到你的錢包了
I saw your wallet.
那里面有好多錢
You got plenty in there.
把錢包拿出來
Take it out.
我們一起幫你回憶一下
Let's look together, jog your memory.
你聽到他說的了
You heard him.
把錢包拿出來
Take out the wallet.
我剛兌了社保的支票
I just cashed my social security check.
我要靠這點錢支撐到月底
It's all I have till the end of the month,
我是不會把它給你的
and I am not giving it to you.
不給嗎
You're not?
我愿意用正確的方式解決這件事
I offered to do this the right way.
但如果你不接受  那我也幫不了你
If you can't accept that, then I can't help you.
你們這是干什么
Aw, come on, guys.
讓我用更簡單的方法替你解決吧
I'm gonna make this real simple for you.
把錢包給我  也許你還能離開
Give me your wallet, and maybe you walk away from this.
我什么都不會給你的
I'm not giving you a damn thing.
不  老頭
Nah, homes.
把錢包給我
Give me your wallet.
先冷靜一下
Let's just stay calm here.
我流汗了嗎  老東西
‭You see me sweating, bitch?
錢包
Wallet. ‭
Wallet.
錢包
差不多有四百塊啊
There's like $400 here.
你還真是嘴硬啊  老家伙
You got some crazy lip on you, old man.
你的命就值四百塊錢嗎
Your life worth 400 bucks?
屠庫  該閃人了
Hey,Tuco, time to bounce.
知道了  你先走
Yeah, go. Go.
算你今天走運  老家伙
You're...one lucky old man.
你干什么  放開我
What the hell? Let go!
放手
Let go!
Let...Let... Let go!
放手
Let go!
‭Let go!
放手
Let go!
把手舉起來
Let me see your hands!
舉起手來
Hands up! Now!
趴下
On the ground!
你就這點能耐
That all you got?
趴到地上
Get on the ground!
瞧你把自己搞的
Look at you.
你要去做證嗎
Are you gonna have to testify?
警察親眼目睹他犯下重罪
The cops witnessed him in the commission of a felony.
我的錢包在他口袋里
My wallet in his pocket.
再加上那把槍  他得蹲個五到十年了
Add the gun -- ‭he gets a 5-to-10 stretch.
兩萬五千塊
$25,000.
絕對是你應得的
You definitely earned it.
只不過你本來可以更加輕松地賺上兩倍
Still, you coulda gotten twice as much for 1/10 the hassle.
還可以幫這個世界清除一個垃圾
You woulda done the world a favor.
你的臉也不會像被棍子掄過一樣
You wouldn't look like someone took a lead pipe to your face.
而且等屠庫出來  他說不定會去找你
Plus, when Tuco gets out, maybe he comes looking for you.
說重點
Get to the point.
我只想問  你為了不開槍而這樣大費周張
Just saying -- you went a long way to not pull that trigger.
到底是為什么
Why?
各大應用市場均可下載
人人美劇APP新版本上線啦
在線看劇全面修復
給你更佳追劇體驗
掃碼即刻下載